<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<page pageId="Page3" pageName="Privacy Policy" title="">
    <abstract></abstract>
    <keywords></keywords>
    <contents>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Normal">Network Mom LLC does not want your private information and does not collect your information via Network Mom Availability.</content>
        </line>
        <line Align="Left">
            <content style="Normal"></content>
        </line>
        <list ListStyle="listDecimalRP">
            <listItem style="Normal">
                <line Align="Left">
                    <content style="Normal">Network Mom Availability needs permission for inbound and outbound network connections to monitor the network, send alerts, and send reports.  Network Mom Availability does not use this to send any information back to Network Mom LLC or any other party.  Network Mom Availability also does not send any emails to Network Mom LLC unless you configure us (presumably erroneously) as an alert or report destination.</content>
                </line>
            </listItem>
            <listItem style="Normal">
                <line Align="Left">
                    <content style="Normal">To enable email alerts, Network Mom Availability needs email account credentials for the "from" email address.  This information is only used to send emails and is only stored on your local Network Mom Availability host.  The password, in particular, is only saved in the Network Mom Availability in-process memory and in the Keychain.  Whether you use iCloud Keychain syncing is configured outside of Network Mom Availability.</content>
                </line>
            </listItem>
            <listItem style="Normal">
                <line Align="Left">
                    <content style="Normal">To use email alerts and reports, you need to configure Network Mom Availability with destination email addresses.  Network Mom Availability saves that configuration on your Network Mom Availability host.  Network Mom Availability uses that information to send email alerts and reports as you configure.  But those email addresses are not harvested by Network Mom Availability.</content>
                </line>
            </listItem>
            <listItem style="Normal">
                <line Align="Left">
                    <content style="Normal">Network Mom LLC also considers the list of devices you monitor as private information.  Network Mom Availability does not harvest this information.  Network Mom Availability includes the list of monitored devices in reports emailed to your report recipients.  This allows your report recipients to know what devices are monitored.  This also constitutes an "emergency backup" allowing easier reconstruction of your Network Mom Availability configuration should a loss of configuration occur.</content>
                </line>
            </listItem>
            <listItem style="Normal">
                <line Align="Left">
                    <content style="Normal">Network Mom Availability uses in-app purchases for monetization.  Those in-app purchases involve sending some data to Apple.  Network Mom LLC receives some aggregated information from Apple regarding in-app purchases (including, but not limited to, number of sales, types of sales, geographic region of sales).  Any data you enter to execute in-app purchases is not sent directly to Network Mom LLC or any other third party.</content>
                </line>
            </listItem>
            <listItem style="Normal">
                <line Align="Left">
                    <content style="Normal">If you choose to send an email to Network Mom LLC (outside of Network Mom Availability, or if you erroneously make us an alert or report recipient), Network Mom LLC may save and respond to your email address.  We may also infrequently send you product information and updates.</content>
                </line>
            </listItem>
        </list>
    </contents>
</page>